Finding Aid for the Claude Lee Finney Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Claude Lee Finney Papers
undated
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0139
5.46 linear feet
- JOHN KEATS: WHEN WAS HE BORN AND WHEN DID HE DIE?, Typescript article by James H. Pershing, with letters from James H. Pershing to Fred Edgcumbe, 6 May 1938, and C. L. Finney, 16 July 1938.
- ROSENBACH MANUSCRIPTS
  - Autograph manuscript of Otho, (4 verses) (Folder 1)
  - Autograph letter of Severn to James Fields, May 25, 1860 (Folder 2)
  - Autograph letter of C. C. Clarke to James Fields, Feb. 9, 1861 (Folder 3)
  - Fragment of Isabella, stanzas XLIX (& last two verses of XLVIII) and LI (and first two verses of LII). (Folder 4)
    Including letter to C. L. Finney from A. S. W. Rosenbach, 26 April 1939.
- "The Poetry of Earth is never dead." Handbook of the Dyce and Forster Collection, South Kensington Museum, Chapman & Hall, 1880. Plate faces p. 78. (Folder 1)
- "Sonnet on the Sea." Published in Champion, Aug. 17, 1817 (Folder 2)
- "Sleep and Poetry." 2-page manuscript. Zweig Estate. (Folder 3)
- "Women, Wine and Snuff." Manuscript with portrait. Library of Trinity College, Cambridge. (Folder 4)
- "I Stood Tiptoe." Sotheby catalogue of valuable printed books, autographs, letters, etc., Jan.-Mar. 1929 (Folder 5)
  Also including the following correspondence:
  Herbert C. Schulz to Katherine Carmichael, 25 August 1943
  Dallas Pratt to Katherine Carmichael, 17 August 1942
  Madeleine B. Stern to Katherine Carmichael, 27 July 1943
  Lloyd A. Brown to Katherine Carmichael, 13 September 1943
  Walter T. Spencer to Katherine Carmichael, 20 May 1942
- "Walks in the North during the Summer of 1818," by Charles Brown. Chapters 1-4, published in the Plymouth & Devenport Weekly Journal, October 1, 8, 15, and 22, 1840 (Folder 1)
- Two letters from Bailey to the Editor of the Oxford Herald. (Folder 2)
- Reminiscences of Keats. His House at Hampstead. Miss Fanny Brawne and Her Peculiarities—The Trials of the Poet. The New York Herald, London, Friday, April 12, 1889, p. 3. (Folder 3)
- "The American Brother of John Keats," by John Gilmer Speed. The Christian Union, 20 August 1892 (Folder 4)
  "An Esculapian Poet -- John Keats"
  Published in The Asclepiad, A Book of Original Research and Observation in the Science, Art, and Literature of Medicine, Preventive and Curative, by Benjamin Ward Richardson, M.D., F.R.S. London: Longmans, Green, and Company, 1894, pp. 138-155. (The Asclepiad was a quarterly magazine.)
- Self-portrait of Joseph Severn, the property of Mr. Severn Storr, "Le Carillon," Harwell, Didcot, Berkshire. (Folder 1)
- Silhouette portrait of Charles Cowden Clarke, from Louis Holman, Boston. (Folder 2)
- Silhouette portraits of George Keats and Mrs. George Keats, from Louis Holman, Boston. (Folder 3)
- Portraits of Edward Jenner, M.D., F.R.S., and Sir Astley Paston Cooper, F.R. S. (Folder 4)
  Letter, dated 7 August 1931, to "Steve" from "Lord W." (Severn Storr?)
  Letter to Keats from Charles Brown, Hampstead, 21 Dec. 1820
- POEMS BY KEATS PUBLISHED IN HOOD’S MAGAZINE AND COMIC MISCELLANY
  - "Sonnet" ("High-mindedness"), Vol. Ill (April 1845), p. 352. (Folder 1)
  - "Old Meg," Vol. I (June 1844), p. 562. (Folder 2)
  - "Sonnet" ("Life’s sea hath been five times at its slow ebb"), Vol. II (September 1844), p. 240. (Folder 3)
  - "Song" ("Hush, hush, tread softly"), Vol. Ill (April 1845), p. 339. (Folder 4)
- ARTICLES ON KEATS
  - "Two Early Reviews of Keats’s First Volume," by Roberta D. Cornelius, March 1925. (Folder 1)
  - "Keats and Mary Tighe," by Earle Vonard Weller, December 1927 (Folder 2)
  - "More Concerning Chapman’s Homer and Keats," by Grace Warren Landrum, December 1927 (Folder 3)
  - "Wordsworth and Keats — A Study in Personal and Critical Impression," by Clarence D. Thorpe, December 1927 (Folder 4)
    Also:
    Notes on George Felton Mathew, 3 pages.
    "List of Newspapers searched for an account of the attack on Mr. Kirkman in December 1818," by Cregoe D. P. Nicholson, 9 September 1938.
    "Ode to Apollo" ("God of the golden bow"), published in Western Messenger, June 1836, p. 763.
- GEORGE FELTON MATHEW’S POEMS: AUTOGRAPH MSS
  - An Epistle to the Author written in their mutual youth by the late John Keats, To George Felton Mathew. (Folder 1)
  - Aphorisms &c. (1-110) (Folder 4)
    Letter, dated 20 October 1891, to "My dear cousin" from Selina Mathew.
- LETTERS BY KEATS FROM VARIOUS AMERICAN COLLECTIONS
  Genealogical Society of Pennsylvania
  1. Fragment of Isabella, stanzas VII & XI.
  2. Letter of Keats to C. C. Clarke, October 9, 1816.
  3. Letter of Keats to George Keats, November 19, 1819.
  4. Letter of Keats to Fanny Brawne, July 8, 1819.
  Massachusetts Historical Society
  1. Letter of Keats to Mrs. Wylie, December 30, 1818.
  Haverford College, Roberts Collection
  1. Letter of Keats to Fanny Brawne, October 13, 1819.
  Maine Historical Society
  1. Letter of Keats to Fanny Brawne, August 5/6, 1819.
- THE EXAMINER (LEIGH HUNT) (poems and criticism in) (copied by hand)
  - "To Solitude," J.K., no. 436, p. 282, May 5, 1816 (Folder 1)
  - "Young Poets," no. 466, December 1, 1816 (Folder 2)
  - "To Kosciusko," J.K., no. 477, p. 107, February 16, 1817 (Folder 6)
  - "Sonnet" ("After dark vapors have oppress’d our plains"), J.K., no. 478, p. 124, February 23, 1817 (Folder 7)
  - "To Haydon," "On Seeing the Elgin Marbles," J.K., no. 480, p. 155, March 9, 1817 (Folder 8)
  - "Written on a blank space at the end of Chaucer’s tale of "The Floure and the Lefe," J.K., no. 481, p. 173, March 16, 1817 (Folder 10)
  - "Literary Notices. No. 29. Poems by John Keats." No. 492, p. 345, June 1, 1817 (Folder 11)
  - "Literary Notices. No. 30. Mr. Keats’s Poems, etc. (Continued.) No. 497, pp. 428-429, July 6, 1817 (Folder 14)
  - "Literary Notices. No. 31. Mr. Keats’s Poems, etc. (Concluded.) No. 498, pp. 443-444, July 13, 1817 (Folder 19)
  - "Two Sonnets on the Grasshopper and Cricket," by John Keats and Leigh Hunt, no. 508, p. 599, September 21, 1817 (Folder 24)
  - "Literary Notices. No. 44." No. 563, pp. 648-649 (October 11, 1818). (Folder 25)
- THE INDICATOR
  - "A Dream, After reading Dante’s episode of Paulo and Francesca," no. 38, p. 304, June 28, 1820 (Folder 304)
- GEORGE FELTON MATHEW: BIOGRAPHICAL INFORMATION
  - "Keats’s Friend Mathew," by Edmund Blunden, reprinted from English, Vol. I, No. 1, pp. 46-55. (Folder 1)
  - Notes on poems by Mathew published in The European Magazine, 1816-18; texts of poems, "On Solitude," "Anacreontic," "Sonnet," "Anacreontic," "Sonnet," "Music," "The Transformation of a Seraph to a Lyre." (Folder 2)
  - "A Genealogical Table of the Mathew Family," communicated by Dr. Crump. (Folder 3)
  - Notes on Hone’s Table Book, etc. (Folder 4)
    Letters to C. L. Finney from T. G. Crump, dated 4 May 1938, August 1938, 24 October 1938, 3 December 1938, and 18 August 1939.
    Letter to C. L. Finney from Fisher Dilke, dated 3 June 1939.
- BIBLIOGRAPHY OF LEIGH HUNT -- MSS. IN UNIVERSITY OF IOWA LIBRARY
  - Professor Finney’s hand-written notes
- ARTHUR A. HOUGHTON COLLECTION
  - Letter from John Keats to George and Georgiana Keats, Sunday, Feb. 14, to Monday, May 3, 1819
  - 76 pages, including several manuscript poems
AMY LOWELL COLLECTION, HARVARD COLLEGE LIBRARY: LETTERS OF KEATS’S BROTHERS AND FRIENDS
John Taylor George Keats 4
Louisville 18 Jun 1820 John Keats George Keats 5
" 8 Nov 1820 " " " " 6
" 3 Mar 1820 Sir " " 7
" 10 Apr 1824 Charles Dilke " " 8
" 20 Apr 1825 " " " " 9
5 Aug 1825 " " " " 10
" 18 Oct 1826 Sir " " 11
" 25 Mar 1828 Charles Dilke " " 12
" 16 Apr 1828 Sir " " 13
New York 12 May 1828 Charles Dilke " "
Louisville 12 Jul 1828 " " " " 14
" 19 Mar 1829 " " " " 15
" 14 Nov 1829 " " " " 16
" 7 May 1830 " " " " 17
" 22 Nov 1830 " " " " 18
" " " " 19
" 23 Nov 1833 " " " " 20
" 14 Mar 1836 " " " " 21
" 1 Mar 1838 " " " " 22
" 15 Nov 1839 Anna H. B. Ward " " 23
Bakewell 25 Sep 1819 Richard Woodhouse John Taylor 24
London 26 Jan 1820 M. Drury " " 25
17 Feb 1821 George Keats Taylor & Hessey 26
AMY LOWELL COLLECTION, HARVARD COLLEGE LIBRARY: LETTERS OF KEATS’S BROTHERS AND FRIENDS (2)
London 19 Feb 1821 Michael Drury John Taylor 27
20 Sep 1820 William Haslam Joseph Severn 29
Naples 1 Nov 1820 " " " " 30
Rome 14 Dec 1820 Charles Brown " " 31
" 24 Dec 1820 John Taylor " " 32
" 11 Jan 1821 Mrs. Brawne " " 33
" 15 Jan 1821 William Haslam " " 34
" 25 Jan 1821 John Taylor " " 35
" 6 Mar 1821 " " " " 36
" 12 Jul 1821 William Haslam " " 37
" 5 Jan 1822 John Taylor " " 38
" 28 Apr 1862 Frederick Locker " " 39
Temple 21 Oct 1818 John Keats Richard Woodhouse 40
" 10 Dec 1818 " " " " 41
" 16 Sep 1820 " " " " 42
Notes on Keats’s method of composi"on 43
Pisa 27 Jul 1820 John Keats P. B. Shelley 44
Hampstead 1 Dec 1818 Richard Woodhouse Charles Brown 45
London 29 Nov 1845 Edward Moxen B. R. Hayden 46
Rome 13 Jan 1821 Mr. Gray 47
Dilton Cottage 4 Dec 1818 Henry Neville Jane Porter 48
Rome 27 Nov 1820 Dr. Clarke 49
" 3 Jan 1821 " " 50
Dunbar 17 Aug 1820 John Keats John Aitkin 51
Genoa 8 Apr 1866 James T. Fields C. C. Clarke 52
AMY LOWELL COLLECTION, HARVARD COLLEGE LIBRARY: LETTERS OF KEATS’S BROTHERS AND FRIENDS (3)
Genoa 2 Dec 1873 James T. Fields Charles and Mary Cowden Clarke 53
Baden-Baden 12 Aug 1887 Sir Mary Cowden Clarke 54
Bayswater 15 Jan 1852 Rev. Thomas Tracy Mary Cowden Clarke 55
" 15 Jan 1852 Donors of the Testimonial Chair Mary Cowden Clarke 56
- BRITISH MUSEUM: GEORGE KEATS’ S BOOK OF AUTOGRAPHS AND TRANSCRIPTS OF KEATS’S POEMS
  - The Pot of Basil, 1818 (Folder 1)
  - Ode. 1818. ("Souls of Poets, dead and gone") (Folder 29)
  - Song. 1818. ("Hence Burgundy, Claret and Port") (Folder 30)
  - Saint Agnes Eve, 1819 (Folder 31)
  - The Eve of Saint Mark. 1819. 37. Saint Agnes Eve. (continued) (Folder 33)
  - Ode on Melancholy, 1819 (Folder 52)
  - Ode to the Nightingale, 1819 (Folder 53)
  - Ode on a Grecian Urn, 1819 (Folder 54)
  - Fragment. 1818. ("Welcome, joy, and welcome, sorrow") (Folder 57)
  - Fragment. 1818. ("Where’s the Poet? Show him! show him!") To Autumn, 1819 (Folder 58)
  - To John Reynolds in answer to his Sonnets on Robin Hood, 1818 (Folder 59)
  - Lines on seeing a Portrait of Keats, By the Author of L’Improvisatrice, I. F. L., 1824 (Folder 61)
  - Elegy on Keats, written by P. B. Shelly. "Adonais" (Folder 62)
  - Sonnet by Mrs. Norton, 1840 (Folder 63)
  - To Miss Keats of Louisville, Ky. (Folder 65)
  - One Daisy and Two Violets. (Sent from the Grave of Keats, Rome, 1880.) (Folder 66)
  - Lines written in the Scotch Highlands. (Folder 67)
    Sonnet. ("This pleasant tale is like a little copse")
    Fragment of Otho, Act I, scene 1, w. 137-41.
- ARTHUR HOUGHTON’s LISTS OF KEATS ITEMS IN THE OWEN D. YOUNG COLLECTION (NEW YORK PUBLIC LIBRARY) AND THE A. EDWARD NEWTON LIBRARY, 1941
  including letter from Arthur Houghton to C. L. Finney, 30 August 1941
BRITISH MUSEUM
10 Jan 1837 J.H. Reynolds Add. 31978 P. 26359
Wentworth Place Tuesday morn Fanny Keats John Keats Ashley MS. P. 4870. 29905
Margate 10 May 1817 Leigh Hunt " " Ashley MS. 4869 29975
BRITISH MUSEUM: AUTOGRAPH LETTERS OF EDWARD HOLMES
Shacklewell Green Leigh Hunt Add. 38523, P. 26359
Aug 1838 " " " "
Liverpool Road 1840? Saturday " " "
Liverpool Road Friday " " Add. 38524 "
Liverpool Road Wednesday " " "
Liverpool Road 17 Jan 1837 Sir Add. 38109 "
- HAMPSTEAD COLLECTION: DILKE*S COPY OF ENDYMION
  Sonnet ("When I have fears that I may cease to be") (1)
  Sonnet. To Homer.
  Sonnet. ("If by dull rhymes our English must be chain’d") (2)
  Sonnet. On a Dream.
  Sonnet. To Sleep.
  Sonnet. On sitting down to read King Lear once again.
  Sonnet. On Fame. ("Fame, like a wayward girl, will still be coy") (3)
  Sonnet. On Fame ("How fever’d is the man, who cannot look")
  Sonnet. To the Nile.
  On sitting down to read King Lear once again.
  Lines on seeing a lock of Milton’s hair. (4)
  Souls of poets dead and gone. (5)
  Lines written in the Highlands after a visit to Burns’s country. (6)
  Ever let the fancy roam. (7)
  Ode to the Nightingale. (9)
  Ode on a Grecian Urn. (11)
  To John Reynolds, in answer to his Robin Hood sonnets. (12)
  Song. ("Hush, hush! tread softly! hush, hush my dear!")
  Biographical material. (15)
BRITISH MUSEUM: AUTOGRAPH LETTERS OF B. R. HAYDON
Thurs morning Hunt B. R. Haydon (Add. 38108. P. 26359)
4 Sep 1816 " " " " "
1814 " " " " "
" " " " "
1815 " " " " "
15 Nov 1816 " " " " "
4 Nov 1815 " " " " "
21 Feb 1816 " " " " "
1 Mar 1816 " " " " "
" " " " (Add.’ 38523)
2 May 1831 John " " " (Add. 33964)
12 Mar 1832 Hunt " " " (Add. 38109)
London 21 Jul 1848 " " " (Add. 38110)
" 15 Feb 1845 Sir " " " (Add. 39168)
" 23 Feb 1845 J. Hutchings " " " "
" 17 Mar 1845 " " " " " "
" 5 May 1849 Sir " " " "
- SCOTTISH NATIONAL PORTRAIT GALLERY
  Fragment of I stood tiptoe, 11. 81-86, and 4 lines not in published version
  Portrait of John Keats
  On sitting down to read King Lear once again
  Fragments of Isabella, stanzas XLIX & LII (first 2 verses missing)
JOHN GREGORY COLLECTION
Burton on Trent 2 Apr 1824 John Taylor B. Bailey
" " " 10 May 1824 " " " "
" " " 9 June 1824 " " " "
" " " 14 June 1824 " " " "
Ceylon 13 Aug 1849 " " " "
London 15 Aug 1823 " " J. H. Reynolds
" Monday " " " " "
" Saturday night Hessey " "
" Saturday " " "
" " " "
" 31 Oct 1837 John Taylor " "
KEATS MUSEUM, HAMPSTEAD (1)
47(1)1-3 London 22 Aug. 1821 Father John Taylor
47(2)1-4 " 15 Apr. 1817 " " "
47(3) " 15 Nov. 1819 James Taylor " "
47(4)
47(5)1-2 " 22 Sep. 1822 Father " "
47(6)1-4 " 28 Mar. 1821 James Taylor " "
47(7)1-2 " 31 Aug. 1820 Father " "
47(8)1-3 " 3 Feb. 1821 " " "
47(9)1-3 " 17 Feb. 1821 " " "
47(11)1-4 Bath 29 June 1820 Hessey " "
47(11)1-4 London 10 Aug. 1820 James Taylor " "
47(12)1-2 " 7 Mar. 1821 Father " "
47(13)1 " 3 Feb. 1821 Brother " "
47(14)1-3 " 4 June 1818 James Taylor " "
47(15)1-3 Retford 12 Oct. 1818 " " " "
47(16)1-3 London 23 Aug. 1820 Father " "
47(17)1-3 " 15 Dec. 1819 " " "
48,1-2 Louisville 26 Nov. 1836
49,1 15 Feb. 1837 Henry R. Wylie
50,1-2 Mrs. Dilke Georginna Keats
51 Dilke Thomas Keats
52(1) Madrid 2 Mar. 1886 Prof. Colim Ralph Thomas
52(2) 27 Feb. Ralph Thomas Frances Keats de Llanos
53 27 Jan. 1890 Eleanor Rosa Llanos Keats
54 Pancras Lane 23 Aug. 1820 John Keats Richard Abbey
59,1-3 Florence 17 Dec. 1829 Miss Brawne Charles Brown
60,1-2 Hampstead 29 Dec. 1829 Mr. Brown
63,1-2 Inverness 7 Aug. 1818
64(1)1-2 2 May 1826 C. W. Dilke Charles Brown
64(2)1-2 Florence 6 Sep. 1824 C. W. Dilke
64(3)1
64(4)1-3 " 17 Dec. 1829 " " "
64(5)1-4 " 20 Jan. 1830 " " " " "
64(7)1-4 " 31 Mar. 1830 " " " " "
64(8)1-4 George Keats
69(1) Biography of Charles Armitage Brown
69(2) " " " " "
69(3)1-7 " " " " "
70,1-13 Walks in the Brown North During the Summer of 1818, by Charles Armitage Brown
72,1-4 Charles Brown C. W. Dilkes
73,1-2 Naples 1 Nov. 1820 Maria Joseph Severn
75,1-2 3 Feb. C. W. Dilkes " "
80,1-2 Rome 24 Mar. 1877 Eleanor Daddy
81,1-2 "Stanzas" by John Keats
KEATS MUSEUM, HAMPSTEAD (2)
84,2 4 Dec. 1818 Neville Jane Porter
84,3 Notes from the diary of Miss Thomazine Leigh
84,4 London 24 Nov. 1815 Sarah Leigh Bailey
"Thrice to Thine" (Macbeth), by Bailey, Rice, and Reynolds
84,5 J. H. Reynolds
84,6,1-4 28 Apr. 1817 Mary Leigh J. H. Reynolds
84,7,1-2 Notes based on a diary, etc. (Rice)
84,9,1-4 Dufours Place 9 Oct. 1815 Tarnsine
91,1-2 John Keats Leigh Hunt
103(1-2) Bawtry 23 Dec. C. W. Dilke Monkton Milnes
103(3)1-2 Dilke
103(5) "
103(6-7) Brighton " " Monkton Milnes
No 1,1-4 Fanny John
No 2,1 Hampstead Maria Dilke
No 2,2 Fanny John
No 2,4 Miss Keats
No 3,1-2,4 Liverpool 30 Jan. 1819 John George
No 4,1 Mr. Taylor Miss Keats
2b Hampstead Horace Smith John Keats
- MISCELLANEOUS
  - Keats letter to Severn, undated (June 6, 1818) — possessed by Howard Eric, New York City (Folder 1)
  - Dedication Page to Poems, presented to G. F. Mathew — possessed by Howard Eric, New York City (Folder 2)
  - "Sleep and Poetry" mss. (157-73, 181-95), Dallas Pratt, 139 E. 40 St., New York City (Folder 3)
  - "Sleep and Poetry" ms., possessed by William M. Elkins (Folder 4)
UNIVERSITY OF ILLINOIS LIBRARY: LETTERS RECEIVED DURING PREPARATION OF "LIFE, LETTERS & LITERARY REMAINS"
1r Louisville 13 May 1845 R. M. Milnes John Jeffrey
3r " 26 July 1845 " " " " " "
7r " 8 Sep. 1845 " " " " " "
9r 13 Feb. 1845 " " " John Taylor
13r Boston 31 Oct. 1845 " " " James Freeman Clarke
15r 22 Dec. 1846 " " " J. H. Reynolds
20r 30 Dec. " " " " " "
24r Newport 22 June " " " " " "
27r 17 Apr. 1848 " " " " " "
31r 8 May 1847 " " " William Haslam
34r London 6 Oct. " " " Joseph Severn
40r " 13 July " " " " " "
54r " 5 May " " " " " "
58r Bayswater 21 Dec. 1846 " " " Charles Cowden Clarke
59r C. C. Clarke Edward Holmes
60r 9 Dec. 1846 R. M. Milnes " " "
64r Bayswater 17 Mar. 1846 " " " Charles Cowden Clarke
78r " " " " " " " " "
84r Stratford 26 Mar. 1846 " " " " " "
86r Bayswater 20 Dec. 1846 " " " " " "
90r 3 Sep. " " " C. W. Dilke
94r 2 June " " " " " "
97r 29 Dec. " " " " " "
103r Kensington 22 Dec. " " " Leigh Hunt
107r " 21 Jan. " " " " " "
111r " 7 May " " " " " "
113r London 20 May 1846 " " " Haydon
115r 6 Jan. 1847 " " " Frederick Leffler
116r Kensington 12 Jan. 1846 " " " George Felton Mathew
118r " 3 Feb. 1847 " " " " " "
124r 11 Feb. 1847 " " " " " "
130r G. F. Mathew Henry Stephens
141r Bideford 9 Feb. 1847 R. M. Milnes Caroline Mathew
(85) Trieste 30 Jan. 1847 " " " A. H. Clough
145r Paris 2 July 1847 " " " John Howard Payne
150r " " G. D. Prentice " " "
152r Clapton 29 May R. M. Milnes Mary Hawilt
154r Eshen 22 May 1847 Mary Hawilt M. Neville
156r St. Johns Wood 2 June 1847 R. M. Milnes George Woodhouse
159r 14 May 1846 " " " A. B. Proslet
161r Camden Town 24 Mar. " " " Coventry Patmore
- THE LITERARY DIARY: OR, IMPROVED COMMON-PLACE-BOOK (etc.) -- RICHARD WOODHOUSE, TEMPLE, NOV. 1818
  - "As doth a Mother wild ...,", Feb. 1818 (Folder 11)
  - "To J.H.R. -- In answer to his Robin Hood sonnets,", 3 Feb. 1819 (Folder 12)
  - "Sonnets on Robin Hood," Yellow Dwarf, 21 Feb. 1818 (Folder 15)
  - "Lines on the Mermaid Tavern" (Folder 16)
  - "Sonnet written by J. H. Reynolds in a collection of M.S. poetry, 8 Feb. 1818 (Folder 17)
  - "Hadst thou lived in days of old,", 14 Feb. 1816 (Folder 18)
  - "To----," J.K., abt. 11 Nov. 1817 from K’s M.S. (Folder 20)
  - "Sonnet," J.K., 1816 ("Oh, how I love ...") (Folder 21)
  - "Sonnet," J.K., 1816 ("As from the darkening gloom ...") (Folder 22)
  - "Sonnet," J. Keats, Jan. 31, 1817 ("After dark vapors ...") (Folder 23)
  - "Sonnet written on a blank space at the end of Chaucer’s tale ’The flowre or the lefe," J.K., Feb. 7, 1817 (Folder 24)
  - "Sonnet to Keats. On reading his sonnet written in Chaucer," J. H. Reynolds, 27 Feb. 1817 (Folder 25)
  - "Sonnet — To a young lady who sent me a laurel crown," J. Keats (Folder 26)
  - "Sonnet — On Mrs. Reynolds’s cat," J. Keats, 16 Jan. 1818 (Folder 27)
  - "On sitting down to read King Lear once again," J. Keats (Folder 28)
  - "Time’s sea has been five years ...," J. Keats, 4 Feb. 1818 (Folder 29)
  - "Lines written upon reading a sonnet by J.H. Reynolds, which will be found p. 17." (Folder 30)
  - "To the Nile," Feb. 6, 1818, J.K. (Folder 31)
  - "Sonnet -- On the Sea," J.K., Champion, 17 Aug 1817 (Folder 32)
  - "Lines Rhymed in a letter received (by J.H.R.) from Oxford, J.K., abt. Midsr 1818 (Folder 33)
  - "Song," J. Keats, abt. Oct. or Dec. 1818 ("In drear-nighted December") 36. "Fragment of an Ode to Apollo," J.Keats. (Folder 34)
  - "Hyperion. Book 1st." (Folder 39)
  - "Book 2nd." (Folder 63)
  - "Book 3rd." 108; "Saint Agnes’ Eve." (Folder 89)
  - "Lines on visiting Staffa,", 26 Mar. 1819 (Folder 138)
  - "When I have fears that I may cease to be,", Feb. 1818 (Folder 144)
  - "Sonnet. To Homer," 1818; "La belle Dame sans Mercy -- A Ballad," 1819 (Folder 146)
  - "Fragment," 1818 ("Welcome joy and welcome sorrow") (Folder 150)
  - "Lines on the Mermaid Tavern (Folder 154)
  - "As Hermes once took to his feathers light." (Folder 156)
  - "Sonnet. To Sleep."(Irregular), 1819; "D°. On the Sonnet." (Irregular) (Folder 158)
  - "Sonnet. On Fame," 1819; "Lines on seeing a lock of Milton’s hair," Jan. 7, 1818. 164. "Ode to the Nightingale,", May 1819 (Folder 160)
  - "Isabella or The Pot of Basil," J.K., written at Teignmouth in the spring of 1818 at the suggestion of J.H.R. (Folder 172)
LETTERS RECEIVED AFTER PUBLICATION OF "LIFE & LETTERS."
164r Bayswater 7 Aug. 1848 R. M. Milnes C. Cowden Clarke
168r 8 Aug. 1848 " " " T. Reseigh
169r 9 Aug. 1848 " " George Woodhouse
171r Newport 10 Aug. 1848 " " John Hamilton Reynolds
175r Kensington 14 Aug. 1848 " " George Felton Mathew
183r Somerset House 15 Aug. 1848 " " " "
185r 15 Aug. " " Jeffrey
189r " " C. W. Dilkes
193r North Brixton 29 Aug. 1848 " " Edward Holmes
194r Edinburgh 22 Aug. 1848 " " Robert Markwood (?)
196r Bath 29 Aug. " " W. S. Landon (?)
200r Bloomsbury 21 Aug. 1848 " " Joseph Bosworth
201r " " Emma Severn
203r Beaconsfield 18 Dec. 1848 " " Francis Edward Venable
206r Colombo, Ceylon 15 Oct. 1848 " " J. B. Bailey
2l4r Ceylon 7 May 1949 " " " "
282r Colombo 11 May 1849 " " " "
BRITISH MUSEUM -- AUTOGRAPH LETTERS OF CHARLES BROWN (Add. 38108, P. 26359)
Venice 3 Sep. 1823 Leigh Hunt 306
Arezzo 8 Oct. 1823 " " 313
Rome 21 Jan. 1824 " " 319
Florence 17 Nov. 1824 " " 335
" 30 Dec. 1824 Sir 340
" 12 Feb. 1825 John Hunt 2
" " " " Sir 4
" 2 Apr. 1825 " 8
" 7 May 1825 " 9
" 8 June 1825 Leigh Hunt 11
" " " " " " 12
" 24 Sep. 1825 " " 16
" 3 Oct. 1825 " " 18
" 30 Oct. 1825 " " 20
" 24 Nov. 1825 " " 22
" 7 Jan. 1826 " " 25
" 24 Jan. 1826 " " 27
" 29 May 1826 " " 30
" 29 Oct. 1826 " " 37
" Feb. 1827 " "
" 3 July 1827 " " 45
9 Aug. 1829 " " 55
" 14 Sep. 1829 " " 57
" 28 Nov. 1829 " " 61
" 1 June 1830 " " 65
Laina Green 20 Sep. 1838 " " 212
New Plymouth 29 Sep. 1898 Sir Charles 177
AMY LOWELL COLLECTION, HARVARD COLLEGE LIBRARY (2)
Hampstead B. Bailey John Keats
Fanny Brawne " "
" " " "
17 Dec 1816 Charles C. Clarke " "
Inverary 18 Jul B. Bailey " "
Winchester 5 Sep John Taylor " "
Margate Aug George Keats " "
any friend who may call " "
Oxford Jane Reynolds " "
Winchester 22 Sep 1819 Richard Woodhouse " "
Winchester 1 Sep John Taylor " "
B. Bailey " "
Margate 16 May 1817 Taylor and Hessey " "
Yarmouth 28 Sep Charles Brown " "
Well Walk 24 Nov James Rice " "
Oxford 14 Sep 1819 Jane Reynolds " "
AMY LOWELL COLLECTION, HARVARD COLLEGE LIBRARY (Letters of John Keats)
John Taylor John Keats
Winchester 17 Aug 1819 Fanny Brawne " "
B. Bailey " "
Wentworth P i. 24 Dec 1818 John Taylor " "
Fleet St. " " " "
Hampstead B. Bailey " "
23 Jan 1818 " " " "
Teignmouth Apr 1818 " " " "
London 10 June 1818 " " " "
Teignmouth James Rice " "
27 Dec 1818 Richard Woodhouse
Taylor " "
Wentworth P1. 18 Dec. 1818 Richard Woodhouse " "
Winchester 5 Sep Hessey " " " " 148
Winchester 14 Aug 1819 B. Bailey " " " " 142
Wentworth P1. James Rice " " " " " " 169
22 June 1818 John Taylor " " " " " " 153
Wentworth Pl. Severn " "
Wentworth Pl. Joseph Severn " "
(fragment) " "
Wentworth P1. 2 Nov 1819 Joseph Severn " "
Well Walk 1 Sep 1818 Jane Reynolds " "
Foot of Llewellyn 27 Jun George Keats " "
10 July 1817 Taylor and Hessey " "
Winchester 24 Aug John Taylor " "
BRITISH MUSUEM: AUTOGRAPH LETTERS OF LEIGH HUNT
4 Jan 1812 Hill Leigh Hunt (Add. 20081. P. 26359)
Mr. Novello " " (Add. 11730. P. 26359)
Chelsea 24 Oct Mary Novello " " (Add. 11730. P. 26359)
" 1 June Vincent " " (Add. 11730. P. 26359)
" 20 Apr 1840 " " " (Add. 11730. P. 26359)
" 24 Apr 1840 " " " (Add. 11730. P. 26359)
Hammersmith 3 Mar 1855 Oilier " " (Add. 33515. P. 26359)
" 8 Oct 1855 " " " (Add. 33515. P. 26359)
" 23 Jan 1858 " " (Add. 33515. P. 26359)
" 7 Jul 1859 " " " (Add. 33515. P. 26359)
Chelsea 18 Mar Sir " " (Add. 31978. P. 26359)
- PIERPONT MORGAN LIBRARY: CHARLES WENTWORTH DILKE’S COMMENTS ON RICHARD MONKTON MILNES’ LIFE, LETTERS AND LITERARY REMAINS OF JOHN KEATS
  Dilke’s annotated copy